Start your engines...
Herbie Fully Loaded is a comedy, family, adventure
film directed by Angela Robinson.
Maggie Peyton, the new owner of Number 53 - the free-wheelin' Volkswagen bug with a mind of its
own - puts the car through its paces on the road to becoming a NASCAR competitor.
Maggie Peyton, played by Lindsay Lohan.
Ray Peyton Sr., played by Michael Keaton.
Trip Murphy, played by Matt Dillon.
Ray Peyton Jr., played by Breckin Meyer.
Kevin, played by Justin Long.
Sally, played by Cheryl Hines.
Herbie: Fully Loaded is a 2005 American sports comedy film directed by Angela Robinson from a
screenplay written by Thomas Lennon, Robert Ben Garant, Alfred Gough, and Miles Millar.
The film stars Lindsay Lohan as the youngest member of an automobile-racing family, Michael Keaton as her father,
Breckin Meyer as her brother, Justin Long as her romantic interest, and Matt Dillon as a competing racer.
Herbie: Fully Loaded features cameo appearances by many NASCAR drivers,
including Jeff Gordon, Jimmie Johnson, Tony Stewart, and Dale Jarrett.
Produced by Robert Simonds, Herbie: Fully Loaded is the sixth and final installment in the Herbie film series, following the
television film The Love Bug (1997), and the first theatrical feature film since Herbie Goes Bananas (1980).
It serves as a legacy sequel to the previous films.
Principal photography took place from August to November 2004, with cinematographer Greg Gardiner, at various locations in California, including
the Riverside International Raceway and Auto Club Speedway; Hansen Dam in Los Angeles; and at Walt Disney Studios in Burbank.
During post-production, editing was completed by Wendy Greene
Bricmont, and the score was composed by Mark Mothersbaugh.
The film premiered at the Las Vegas Motor Speedway on May 10, 2005, and Walt Disney
Pictures released it theatrically in the United States on June 24.
Distributed by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution, Herbie: Fully Loaded was a box office success,
grossing over $144 million worldwide against its production budget of $50 million.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and moviegoers, but a
positive response from fans of the Herbie franchise.
The film explores themes of car race, sports, victory, sequel, slapstick comedy.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.